# Shay **Kalyan**



Auckland, New Zealand



+64 27 727 6866



shaykalyan@outlook.com



github.com/xShay

# Objective

Software Engineer in Development

#### Profile

Currently I am an undergraduate student at the University of Auckland, undertaking a Bachelor of Engineering specialising in Software Engineering. My passion in technology has placed me in the position I am in today, pursuing the rapidly growing field of Computer Science and Software. I look forward to contributing to the industry and aid in the evolution of our day to day life.

## Education

#### Bachelor of Engineering (Honours), Software Engineering

2012 - 2016

The University of Auckland CGPA: **8.7** / 9.0.

#### National Certificate of Educational Achievement (NCEA)

2009 – 2011

Otumoetai College Level 3 with Excellence.

# Awards and Certificates

#### Dean's Honours List

2012, 2013, 2014

University of Auckland

Awarded to the top 5% of Software Engineering students in the academic year.

#### First in Course Award

University of Auckland

- SOFTENG 370: Operating Systems.
- SOFTENG 325: Software Architecture.
- SOFTENG 306: Software Engineering Design 2.
- COMPSCI 314: Modern Data Communications.
- SOFTENG 206: Software Engineering Design 1.
- ENGGEN 131: Introduction to Engineering Computation and Software Development.

# Recent Projects

#### Pebble Watchface: Trace

Personal Project

Technologies: C Language, Javascript, jQuery Mobile, Pebble SDK 2.0.

- Designed and created a minimalist watchface for the Pebble smartwatch, deployed via the Appstore.
- Over 1,500 unique users of the application.

#### Android Application: Contacts Now

University Project – Individual

Technologies: Java, SQLite, Android SDK.

- Designed and developed a contact management application for the Android platform.
- Implemented an interactive contact card with additional functionality such as navigating to an address.

# **Employment**

#### Microsoft

Dec 2014 - Feb 2015

Software Engineering Intern

• Implemented support for dynamically allocating virtual machines for the execution of tests on software builds in a test orchestration system used by customers internal to the company.

#### Sapphire Solutions Limited

Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Software Development Intern

- Redesigned, constructed, and deployed the company's website using modern HTML5 and CSS3 standards.
- Increased web presence in competitive online search by applying Search Engine Optimization (SEO).
- Created software tools in C# for internal and external use to assist the operations of the business.
- Prepared client computers for off-site installation.

#### Target Road Tyres

lan 2012 - Feb 2013

Administrator / Developer

- Involved in creating a 10 page website to allow the company to showcase thier products and services.
- Implemented standard Search Engine Optimization (SEO) techniques.
- Tasked with administrative responsibilities including managing stock and providing tailored solutions for customers.

# Volunteer Work

#### Software Engineering Students Association

2015

Part IV Representative

- Assisted in organizing and promoting events hosted by the student led association.
- Provided a friendly and informative communication channel for students to elevate any concerns and provide feedback relating to courses or the university in general.

#### Peer Support Programme

2011

Student Mentor

- Participated in one-on-one interaction with first year college students to provide mentorship.
- Helped peers adjust to college life by listening to and resolving any academic or social issues they were experiencing.

### Skills

#### Languages

- Java
- **C**#
- **-** C++
- **-** C
- Python

#### **Internet Technologies**

- HTML5 & CSS3
- Javascript

#### Mobile Development

Android

#### Systems

- Windows XP, 7, 8
- Mac OS X 10.10
- Linux

# Academic Transcript

Available on Request